{
      "lessons" : { 
        "lesson1": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu como peixe", "answer": "i eat fish"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Você bebe agua", "answer": "you drink water"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Eu como frango", "answer": "i eat chicken"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eu como carne bovina no almoço", "answer": "i eat beef for lunch"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eu como pão no café da manhã", "answer": "i eat bread for breakfast"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Eu não bebo um copo de água", "answer": "i don't drink a glass of water"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Você come peixe no jantar?", "answer": "do you eat fish for dinner?"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Eu não bebo uma xícara de café", "answer": "i don't drink a cup of coffee"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Você bebe chá no café da manhã?", "answer": "do you drink tea for breakfast?"}
  ],
  "lesson2": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu falo inglês com minha mãe", "answer": "i speak english with my mother"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Você fala espanhol com seu primo?", "answer": "do you speak spanish with your cousin?"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Eu estudo espanhol com minha irmã", "answer": "i study spanish with my sister"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Você estuda frances com seu pai?", "answer": "do you study french with your father?"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eu gosto de estudar alemão com meu irmão", "answer": "i like to study german with my brother"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Eu nao gosto de falar frances com meu avô", "answer": "i eat chicken"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Você gosta de estudar com seu irmao de tarde?", "answer": "i eat chicken"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Eu nao gosto de falar francês a noite", "answer": "i eat chicken"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Eu falo alemão com meus pais de tarde", "answer": "i eat chicken"}
  ],
  "lesson3": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu preciso falar com meu filho", "answer": "i need to speak with my son"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Você quer estudar com seu sobrinho?", "answer": "do you want to study with your nephew?"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Eu quero estudar alemão esse ano", "answer": "i want to study german this year"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eu preciso falar com você semana que vem", "answer": "i need to study with you next week"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eu quero falar com seu sobrinho amanhã", "answer": "i need to speak with your nephew tomorrow"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Eu preciso beber um copo de água agora", "answer": "i need to drink a glass of water now"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Você precisa falar com minha filha?", "answer": "do you need to speak with my daughter?"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Eu nao quero beber café no café da manhã", "answer": "i don't want to drink coffee for breakfast"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Você quer beber um copo de água?", "answer": "do you want to drink a glass of water?"}
  ],
  "lesson4": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eles precisam trabalhar no mercado amanhã?", "answer": "do they need to work in the store tomorrow?"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Eu gosto de tocar piano no escritório", "answer": "i like to play the piano in the office"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Nós gostamos de jogar futebol com seu tio", "answer": "we like to play soccer with your uncle"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eu não quero estudar chinês com meu irmão", "answer": "i don't want to study chinese with my brother"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Onde eles querem estudar amanhã?", "answer": "where do they want to study tomorrow?"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Elas precisam trabalhar no parque hoje", "answer": "they need to work in the park today"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Nós precisamos trabalhar no banco amanhã", "answer": "we need to work in the bank tomorrow"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Quando elas querem tocar piano?", "answer": "when do they want to play the piano?"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Nós trabalhamos no banco todos os dias", "answer": "we work in th bank every day"}
  ],
  "lesson5": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu vou para o cinema todos os dias", "answer": "i go to the movies every day"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Você quer ir para o escritório comigo?", "answer": "do you want to go to the office with me?"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Eles vão para o shopping de manhã", "answer": "they go to the mall in the morning"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Onde você quer ir amanhã?", "answer": "where do you want to go tomorrow?"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Nós precisamos vir para a igreja amanhã", "answer": "we need to come to church tomorrow"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Nós precisamos ir ao centro", "answer": "we need to go downtown"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Eu não gosto de ir para o escritório", "answer": "i don't like to go to the office"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "O que você quer comer no shopping?", "answer": "what do you want to eat in the mall?"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Eles querem ir para a rodoviaria", "answer": "they want to go to the bus station"}
  ],
  "lesson6": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Ela quer escrever um livro", "answer": "she wants to write a book"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Ele precisa ler o livro agora", "answer": "he needs to read the book now"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Ela gosta de escrever de manhã", "answer": "she likes to write in the morning"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ele não quer escrever um livro", "answer": "he doesn't want to write a book"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Ela precisa ler o livro agora?", "answer": "does he need to read the book now?"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Ela come pão no café da manhã", "answer": "she eats bread for breakfast"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Ela não bebe aguá no almoço", "answer": "she doesn't drink water for lunch"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Ele trabalha no escritório?", "answer": "does he work in the office"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Ela não gosta de estudar no parque", "answer": "she doesn't like to study in the park"}
  ],
  "lesson7": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu tenho que ir para a escola hoje", "answer": "i have to go to school today"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Ela tem que trabalhar hoje", "answer": "she has to work today"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Eles preferem comer frango no jantar", "answer": "they prefer to eat chicken for dinner"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eu trabalho como um garçom", "answer": "i work as a waiter"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Nós ainda gostamos de estudar de manhã", "answer": "we still like to study in the morning"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Por que você prefere ir para o cinema?", "answer": "why do you prefer to go to the movies?"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Ela prefere trabalhar no banco", "answer": "she prefers to work in the bank"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Quanto dinheiro você tem?", "answer": "how much money do you have?"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Quanto dinheiro ela tem?", "answer": "how much money does she have?"}
  ],
  "lesson8": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu acordo as 8 h todos os dias", "answer": "i wake up at 8 am every day"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Nós precisamos acordar as 6 h amanhã", "answer": "we need to wake up at 6 am tomorrow"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Ela não quer dormir aqui hoje", "answer": "she doesn't want to sleep here today"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eu gosto desse tipo de livros", "answer": "i like this kind of books"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Elas vão para a cama as 23 h", "answer": "they go to bed at at 11 pm"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Ela tem um emprego novo", "answer": "she has a new job"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Eles trabalham cedo todos os dias?", "answer": "do they work early every day?"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Nós precisamos ir para a escola cedo", "answer": "we need to go to school early"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Ele tem um carro pequeno?", "answer": "does he have a small car?"}
  ],
  "lesson9": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu quero comprar um livro novo", "answer": "i want to buy a new book"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Nós não queremos comprar um carro agora", "answer": "we don't want to buy a car now "},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Eles querem vender duas passagens", "answer": "they want to sell two tickets"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ela gosta de ir para o aeroporto?", "answer": "does she like to go to the airport?"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eles precisam ir para a Inglaterra amanhã", "answer": "they need to go to england tomorrow"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "O avião decola as 16 h", "answer": "the plane takes off at 4 pm"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Eles precisam vender a bolsa de mão hoje", "answer": "they need to sell the handbag today"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Meu irmão quer comprar um carregador novo", "answer": "my brother wants to buy a new charger"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Eu não quero comprar uma xícara de café", "answer": "i don't want to buy a cup of coffee"}
  ],
  "lesson10": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Ele caça animais todos os dias", "answer": "he hunts animals every day"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Nós preferimos alimentar nosso cachorro", "answer": "we prefer to feed ou dog"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Ela gosta de brincar com o gato dela", "answer": "she likes to play with her cat"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Pássaros gostam de voar à noite", "answer": "birds like to fly at night"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eles jogam futebol com o gerente deles", "answer": "they play soccer with their manager"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Ele trabalha com o pai dele no escritório", "answer": "he works with his father in the office"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Nós precisamos levar nosso filho para a escola", "answer": "we need to take our son to school"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Eu quero ler o livro dela", "answer": "i want to read her book"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Elas querem estudar com a prima delas", "answer": "they want to study with their cousin"}
  ],
  "lesson11": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Por que ele está triste?", "answer": "why is he sad?"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Ele está triste porque ele não tem dinheiro", "answer": "he is sad because he doesn't have money"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Por que ela está brava?", "answer": "why is she angry?"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ela está brava porque ela não quer ir", "answer": "she is angry because she doesn't want to go"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Por que você está com sede?", "answer": "why are you thirsty?"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Eu estou com sede porque eu não tenho água", "answer": "I'm thirsty because i don't have water"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Onde você está?", "answer": "where are you?"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Ela está no banco com a mãe dela", "answer": "she is in the bank with her mother"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Nós estamos no parque com nosso cachorro", "answer": "we are in the park with our dog"}
  ],
  "lesson12": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Ela caminha com a irmã dela de manhã", "answer": "she walks with her sister in the morning"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Nós não corremos de tarde", "answer": "we don't run in the afternoon"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Ele caminha ao redor do bairro?", "answer": "does he walk around the neighborhood?"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ela está atrás da biblioteca", "answer": "she is behind the library"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "O carro está em frente ao banco", "answer": "the car is in front of the bank"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Nós não queremos ir para a festa", "answer": "we don't want to go to the party"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Elas estão atrás do shopping", "answer": "they are behind the mall"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "O livro está em cima da mesa", "answer": "the book is over the table"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Os livros estão embaixo da mesa", "answer": "the books are under the table"}
  ],
  "lesson13": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu quero saber sobre isso", "answer": "i want to know about this"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Nós precisamos saber se ele vem", "answer": "we need to know if he comes"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Meu primo não mora aqui", "answer": "my cousin doesn't live here"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ele sabe a verdade?", "answer": "does he know the truth?"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Meus parentes moram perto da praia", "answer": "my relatives live near the beach"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Ela quer ir para o restaurante de novo", "answer": "she wants to go to the restaurant again"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Eu sei tocar piano muito bem", "answer": "i know how to play the piano very well"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Ela fala inglês muito bem", "answer": "she speaks english very well"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Nós moramos longe do escritório", "answer": "we live far from the office"}
  ],
  "lesson14": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Nós sempre pensamos sobre os animais", "answer": "we always think about the animals"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Ele geralmente não entende o pai dele", "answer": "he usually doesn't understand his father"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Ela não gosta de conversar de manhã", "answer": "she doesn't like to talk in the morning"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Nós precisamos estudar geografia", "answer": "we need to study geography"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eles precisam estudar com os colegas deles", "answer": "they need to study with their classmates"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Ela falta aula quando ela está doente", "answer": "she skips class when she is sick"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Você prefere fazer o teste de tarde?", "answer": "do you prefer to take the test in the afternoon?"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Nós já sabemos ler", "answer": "we already know how to read"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Minha irmã não gosta de biologia", "answer": "my sister doesn't like biology"}
  ],
  "lesson15": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu posso comprar um carro novo", "answer": "i can buy a new car"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Você não pode comer aqui", "answer": "you can't eat here"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Você consegue vender o carro dela?", "answer": "can you sell her car?"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ela não consegue dormir no parque", "answer": "she can't sleep in the park"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eu trabalho enquanto ela estuda", "answer": "i work while she studies"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Ele trabalha enquanto eles dormem", "answer": "he works while they sleep"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Eu não posso machucar a perna de novo", "answer": "i can't hurt the leg again"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Ela não consegue vender o carro dela", "answer": "she can't sell her car"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Eu posso ir para o cinema com você", "answer": "i can go to the movies with you"}
  ],
  "lesson16": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu gostaria de estudar com você", "answer": "i would like to study with you"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Ela gostaria de jogar vôlei amanhã", "answer": "she would like to play volleyball tomorrow"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Você gostaria de ir para o banco?", "answer": "would you like to go to the bank?"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eu trabalho nessa empresa desde janeiro ", "answer": "i work in this company since january"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Ela quer vender a casa dela em setembro", "answer": "she wants to sell her house in september"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Nós não gostaríamos de estudar hoje", "answer": "we wouldn't like to study today"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Ela gostaria de estudar inglês?", "answer": "she would like to study english"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Ela almoça com os pais dela no sábados", "answer": "she has lunch with her parents on saturdays"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Nós gostamos de jantar com nosso filho", "answer": "we like to have dinner with our son"}
  ],

  "lesson17": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Ela deveria estudar mais de manhã", "answer": "she should study more in the morning"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Nós deveríamos vender o nossa passagem", "answer": "we should sell our ticket"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Ele não deveria beber cerveja no almoço", "answer": "he shouldn't drink beer for lunch"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ela  deixa o celular dela atrás da mesa", "answer": "she leaves her cell phone behind the table"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Elas deveria ir para o escritório com ele", "answer": "they should go to the office with him"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Eu gosto de correr com eles", "answer": "i like to run with them"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Ela não pode estudar com nós", "answer": "she can't study with us"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Eu preciso ir ao cinema com ela", "answer": "i need to go to the movies with her"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Ela gostaria de morar com ele", "answer": "she would like to live with him"}
  ],
  "lesson18": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Ele deve trabalhar aqui até abril", "answer": "he must work here until april"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Você deve perguntar sobre o jogo", "answer": "you must ask about the game"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Ela deve estar feliz com a entrevista", "answer": "she must be happy with the interview"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eles devem estar na parada de ônibus", "answer": "they must be in the bus stop"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Esse carro deve ser confortável", "answer": "this car must be comfortable"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Ela deve sair da prefeitura agora mesmo", "answer": "she must leave the city hall right now"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Eu preciso tomar o remédio amanhã", "answer": "i need to take the medicine tomorrow"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Quantos anos você tem?", "answer": "how old are you?"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Ele tem 21 anos", "answer": "he is 21 years old"}
  ],
  "lesson19": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Ela está esperando por ele", "answer": "she is waiting for him"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Nós estamos assistindo o filme juntos", "answer": "we are watching the movie together"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Ele está ajudando o filho dele", "answer": "he is helping his son"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eles estão assistindo série", "answer": "they are watching series"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eu gostaria de almoçar com ela", "answer": "i would like to have lunch with her"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Eu já tenho muitos problemas", "answer": "i already have many problems"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Ele está ocupado", "answer": "he is busy"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Ela gosta de tirar um cochilo de tarde", "answer": "she likes to take a nap in the afternoon"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Você precisa conversar com aquele homem?", "answer": "do you need to talk with that man?"}
  ],
  "lesson20": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Ela não conseguiu comer o sanduíche", "answer": "She couldn't eat the sandwich"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Ele conseguiu dirigir o carro novo dele", "answer": "he could drive his new car"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Eu poderia estudar italiano com você", "answer": "i could study italian with you"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Você consegue ouvir esse barulho?", "answer": "can you hear this noise?"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eles querem comprar o mesmo celular", "answer": "they want to buy the same cell phone"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Eu não consigo dormir com esse barulho", "answer": "i can't sleep with this noise"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Ela está estudando inglês sozinha", "answer": "she is studying english by herself"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Eles estão assistindo o filmes sozinhos", "answer": "they are watching the movie by themselves"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Ele quer ler o livro novo sozinho", "answer": "he wants to read the new book by himself"}
  ],
    "lesson21": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu pensarei sobre isso", "answer": "I will think about it"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Ele entenderá espanhol muito bem", "answer": "He will understand spanish very well"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Nós iremos para o médico semana que vem", "answer": "We will go to the doctor next week"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ela não morará com o irmão dela", "answer": "She won't live with her brother"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eles não esperarão por você amanhã", "answer": "They won't wait for you tomorrow"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Ela caminhará com a filha dela hoje?", "answer": "Will she walk with her daughter today?"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Eu gostaria de fazer novos amigos", "answer": "i would like to make new friends"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Você sempre faz uma bagunça aqui", "answer": "you always make a mess here"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Ela fará um bolo de chocolate?", "answer": "Will she make a chocolate cake?"}
    ],
    "lesson22": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu vou comprar um ceular para minha filha", "answer": "I'm going to buy a cell phone for my daughter"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Eles vão vender o carro deles", "answer": "They are going to sell their car"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Nós vamos mudar nossas regras", "answer": "we are going to change our rules"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Ele não vai dormir aqui hoje", "answer": "he isn't going to sleep here today"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Você pode trazer uma caixa vazia?", "answer": "Can you bring an empty box?"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Eles vão estudar juntos esse ano", "answer": "They are going to study together this year"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Felizmente ela está aqui com nós", "answer": "Fortunately she is here with us"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Ele tem certeza que ele vai comprar o carro", "answer": "He is sure that he is going to buy the car"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Ela realmente deveria ir para o médico", "answer": "she really should go to the doctor"}
    ],
    "lesson23": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Há um carro em frente ao parque", "answer": "There is a car in front of the park"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Tem três livros novos em cima do sofá", "answer": "There are three new books over the couch "},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Tem uma jaqueta de couro dentro do armário?", "answer": "is there a leather jacket inside the wardrobe?"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Há um cachorro correndo ao redor da casa", "answer": "There is a dog walking around the house"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Não tem um bolo de cholocate no escritório", "answer": "There isn't a chocolate cake in the office"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Quantas roupas você tem aqui?", "answer": "how many clothes do you have here?"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Ele não gosta de vestir aquela camisa verde", "answer": "he doesn't like to wear that green shirt"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Ela gostaria de tirar o moletom dela", "answer": "she would like to take off her sweatshirt"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Nós deveríamos comprar meias novas", "answer": "we should buy new socks"}
    ],
    "lesson24": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "Eu tenho que enviar os documentos para ela", "answer": "I have to send the documents to her"},
    {"number": 2, "question": "Ela deveria enviar outra mensagem amanhã", "answer": "She should send another message tomorrow"},
    {"number": 3, "question": "Nós devemos ficar aqui até semana que vem", "answer": "we must stay here until next week"},
    {"number": 4, "question": "Eles geralmente chegam no escritório de manhã", "answer": "They usually arrive in the office in the morning"},
    {"number": 5, "question": "Eu vou chegar cedo na festa ", "answer": "I'm going to arrive early in the party"},
    {"number": 6, "question": "Há um gato no telhado", "answer": "There is a cat on the roof"},
    {"number": 7, "question": "Tem sete livros na prateleira", "answer": "there are seven books on the shelf"},
    {"number": 8, "question": "Com que frequencia você vai ao cinema?", "answer": "How often do you go to the movies?"},
    {"number": 9, "question": "Ao invés de assistir um filme, eu quero ler um livro", "answer": "instead of watching a movie, i want to read a book"}
    ],
    "mock": [
    {"number": 1, "question": "", "answer": ""},
    {"number": 2, "question": "", "answer": ""},
    {"number": 3, "question": "", "answer": ""},
    {"number": 4, "question": "", "answer": ""},
    {"number": 5, "question": "", "answer": ""},
    {"number": 6, "question": "", "answer": ""},
    {"number": 7, "question": "", "answer": ""},
    {"number": 8, "question": "", "answer": ""},
    {"number": 9, "question": "", "answer": ""}
    ]
  
  }}